Guide to the Rice University Laboratory Equipment collection, ca. 1920s-2000s UA 384
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
- Series I: Laboratory Equipment
  - DC Ammeter, 1952; annex_106; Dirty medium-sized wooden box with two black nubs and hinges on front and a leather strap and latch on top
    Manufactured by Weston Electrical Instrument Corp; used to measure current in direct current (DC) circuits
  - DC AC Voltmeter, n.d.; annex_107; Dirty wooden box with hinges on side and leather strap on top; front has label of Rice Insitute Electrical Engineering
    Manufactured by Weston Electrical Instrument Corp; used to measure voltage in electrical circuits
  - Portable Test Meter, 1934; annex_108; Greenish medium-sized wooden box with white lettering on the front
    Manufactured by General Electric; used to test batteries
  - Single Range Potentiometer Indicator, annex_109; Open lightly-colored wooden box with directions and various knobs as well as a small slightly arched viewing window and clear red label on front
    Manufactured by Leeds and Northrup Co; used to measure voltage in circuits
  - Random Noise Generator, ca. 1969; annex_110; Medium large black metal box with semicircular viewing window, instruction manual, and 4 knobs and 2 input spots
    Manufactured by General Radio Co
  - Transformer, n.d.; annex_111
    Manufactured by General Radio Co; used to convert low voltage to high voltage or vice versa
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    Black rounded box with 6 varying sized brass-colored cylinders with holes cut through them and large hole through center of object
  - Battery Test, n.d.; annex_112; Medium sized wooden box with metallic handle and two holes in front and old paper tag hanging on it
    Manufactured by Northern Electric Co Ltd
  - Sound Level Meter, ca. 1946; annex_113; Large black box with metal corners and large latch on front
  - Size Measuring Device, n.d.; annex_114; T shaped metallic and wooden device with ruler on the crossbar
    Manufactured by Leeds and Northrup; used to measure length
  - Mercury Arc Rectifier Tube, ca. 1913; annex_115; Clear glass tube with two arms with black tips supported by black blocks and string; contains a little liquid mercury
    Manufactured by General Electric; used to convert alternating to direct current or vice versa
  - Transistor, n.d.; annex_116; Clear plastic tube with white plastic cap and three wires inside, 1 that is large and red and 2 that are white and red striped and smaller
    Manufactured by Westinghouse Semiconductors; used to control a large voltage with a small voltage
  - Circuit Chips (3), ca. 1984-1987; annex_117; 3 gray and golden plastic rectangles of varying size with metallic feet inside clear plastic container on top of black foam
    Manufactured by Motorola; purpose unknown
  - Logic Chip, ca. 1990s; annex_118; Large gray and golden recatngular piece with metal feet inside clear plastic container on top of black foam
    Manufactured by LSI logic; purpose unknown
  - Large Vacuum Tubes (5), n.d.; annex_119; 5 large glass tubes inside a gray box
    Manufactured by Amperex; used in old electronic equipment
  - Dial Variable Resistor Type 314, n.d.; annex_120; Wooden rectangular base with black circular piece and rotating contact controlled by black knob on top; labelled as C13A in white lettering
    Manufactured by General Radio Co; used to adjust resistance in a circuit
  - Variable Resistor, n.d.; annex_121; Wooden rectangular base with circular ceramic wheel piece and black dial knob as well as 3 protruding gray cylinders
    Manufactured by Ohmite Manufacturing Co; used to adjust resistance in a circuit
  - Precision Condenser with Calibration Plaque, ca. 1948; annex_122; Paper calibration certificate inside cover; large wooden box with black metal handle and latch
    Manufactured by General Radio Co; used to hold charge charge in an electrical circuit
  - Plant and Animal Cell Models, annex_123; Plaster models with brightly colored figures
  - Microscope Video Camera with Instruction Manual, n.d.; annex_124; Paper instruction manual with pale green and metal box with circular plug on end
    Manufactured by Hamamatsu; used to photograph microscope images
  - Precision Capacitor, ca. 1955; annex_125; Large wooden box with dial, handle, and small recatngular viewing window inside
    Manufactured by General Radio Co; used to hold charge in a circuit
  - Portable Double Bridge, n.d.; annex_126; Yellowish brown wooden box with leather handle and red label
    Manufactured by General Electric Co; used to measure resistance in four terminal resistors
  - Battery Charger, n.d.; annex_127; Small gray and black plastic box wrapped in gray cord
    Manufactured by WP Instruments Inc
  - Thermocouple Potentiometer, n.d.; annex_128; Medium sized wooden box with latch, two small metallic brackets, and a Rice patch label on the front
    Manufactured by General Electric; used to measure voltage with correction for temperature
  - Sonicator Bath, n.d.; annex_129; Gray metal box-shaped pot on top of black base with dial and indicator light
    Manufactured by Fisher Scientific; uses sound waves inside water to mix solutions
  - Human Ear Model, n.d.; annex_130; Plaster model with removable pieces
  - Polyphase Wattmeter, 1954; annex_131; Medium sized wooden box with a latch and circular pieces on front and two holes on the side
    Manufactured by General Electric; used to measure power
  - pH Meter, ca. 1955; annex_132; Medium sized wooden box with hinged side compartment
    Manufactured by Beckman; used to measure acidity
  - Gram Electrobalance, ca. 1962; annex_133; Medium sized metal rounded box with shades of blue, various knobs, and sliding glass door for weighing compartment
    Manufactured by Cahn; used to measure mass